All right, so I am a PhD student at The University of Alabama in Huntsville. There's a lot that goes into that.
身为阿拉巴马大学亨茨维尔分校的博士生 还是有不少说道的
It's a very difficult thing for me.
我念得还挺辛苦
I'm studying under  Dr. Jason Cassibry. Really fun.
我的导师是Jason Cassibry博士 很有意思
The other day, someone from the university reaches out and they said, Hey, doesn't your student, Destin, doesn't he do talks occasionally or whatever?
有一天学校里的人问他 "诶 你学生Destin是不是偶尔会搞点演讲什么的?"
It was the American Astronautical Society.
谁问的? 美国宇航学会
This is a group that discusses the future of space exploration, aerospace CEOs,
这是一个讨论太空探索未来的研讨会 成员包括航空航天CEO
industry leaders, students, government officials.
行业领袖 学生和政府官员
They've been having these discussions since the 1950s.
这个学会上世纪50年代(1954年)就有了
They asked if I would do what I call a talky talk.
他们问我愿不愿意上去"简单讲两句"
Now, usually I say no to talky talks because I like to prepare and get it right, and it just takes a long time.
我其实不爱搞这种"随便唠唠" 我更喜欢给足时间充分准备的那种演讲
Plus, I only do a few of those a year, and I just didn't know if this was the right thing to do.
另外 这种活我每年也只干几次 不知道该不该接
But the more I got to thinking about it, the more I realized that the people that were going to be in this room are the movers and shakers in the aerospace industry.
但后来我仔细一琢磨才知道 参会的人都是航空航天业的推动者和变革者
And these are the people that are doing things like planning the mission architecture to go back to the moon.
他们当中有的人可能会负责重返月球任务的规划
And when I looked at the name of the talk, it was advancing space from Leo to Lunar and Beyond, or at least this is the symposium.
我又看了下研讨会的主题 "探索太空 从近地轨道到月球 再到远方"
It's the 2023 von Braun Space exploration symposium.
"2023 冯·布劳恩太空探索研讨会"
Now, Werner von Braun, or von Braun, depending on what way you pronounce his name, was the main architect behind the Apollo program, which is when we went to the moon.
韦恩赫尔·冯·布劳恩 是阿波罗工程的总设计师 也就是人类登月的时候
Right now, America is doing what's called the Artemis program.
而现在 美国正在搞一个"阿尔忒弥斯计划"
The Artemis program is our effort to go back to the moon to take humans there now with new technology.
阿尔忒弥斯计划打算用新技术送人类重返月球
It's very interesting.
很有意思
With most talky talks that I do, I like to provide an external perspective to the organization or the company that's asked me to come in and speak.
以前我多数演讲中 我都喜欢从外部视角来看待请我来演讲的组织或公司
In this case, all the people in front of me are the most important industry leaders in aerospace.
而这次 我面前的所有人都是航空航天领域中领头的行业领袖
I thought about what it would look like to take a third-party perspective view of Artemis.
所以我在想 以第三方视角会怎么看阿尔忒弥斯计划
I thought that would be pretty good.
我感觉这思路还不错
But the more I started digging into Artemis, the more I realized there might be some issues in how people communicate about it.
但随着我深入了解阿尔忒弥斯计划 我越发感觉大伙沟通好像出了问题
There's some architecture problems that people are unwilling to talk about these days because of how they got there politically.
大伙现在不愿谈论这种任务结构问题 因为这些问题有些政治因素
I was like, You know what? I just want to go say the thing that nobody's saying. That's what I decided to do.
而我打算把这些大伙都不敢碰的话题说出来
Now, a lot of people I respect, when I was doing my research and asking these questions, they said, Be careful, Destin.
当我调查阿尔忒弥斯计划的时候 我了采访很多值得尊敬的人 他们提醒我要小心
If you say certain things, this might change your relationship with NASA forever.
有些事你要是说出来 你和NASA的关系可能就会永远发生改变了
I thought about it and I decided, You know what? This is the truth and this is what needs to be said.
我想了想 决定了 这些事实总该有个人讲出来
And NASA, please don't hate me.
另外NASA也请不要记恨我
In all seriousness though, I'm nervous about this talk before I go in. You'll see that.
我现在说着轻松 但在我真触碰话题之前我还是很紧张的 你们一会能看到
I decided just to play the talk for you and let you see what this is like.
我决定把这段演讲给大家看
Now, to be clear, being a YouTuber means nothing in this room.
要说明的是 我这个千万粉的油管博主在这个研讨会上屁都不是
The first part of the talk is me trying to establish credibility within the aerospace industry by saying some of the things that I've done.
所以我演讲的前半部分 是在讲述我做过的事情 和那帮航天大佬建立信任
I've done the Defense Acquisition University. I know what it means to develop a system that's going to be human-rated.
我读过国防军需大学 知道研发一套载人系统意味着什么
I have to establish that.
我要让大家知道这点
But also I have to sprinkle in a little of the, I'm the YouTuber guy who you think I am.
但我还得稍微拽一点 就是那种油管网红的感觉
And then in the end, I want to ask the difficult questions.
在最后 我会问几个刁钻的问题
So for me, this was an exercise in something called rhetoric.
因此对我来 这就像是一次"修辞"的练习
Rhetoric is trying to persuade somebody to a certain position, and that's what I was doing here.
Rhetoric 修辞 = logos 理性 + pathos 感性 + ethos 人设
I thought you would enjoy being in the room.
希望大家能喜欢我的演讲
This is me in a room I usually wouldn't get to be in, and I thought you might like to peek in on this and see what I had to say.
我很难有机会参加这样的研讨会 我希望大家能喜欢看到我演讲的内容
I would love to know what your thoughts are with my points about Artemis.
我也很希望知道你们怎样看我对阿尔忒弥斯计划的评价
That's it. We'll see how it works.
拭目以待吧
I almost forgot.
差点忘了
At some point, I'm going to show you this year's sticker design for patron.
我到时候会给大家展示今年为赞助者设计的贴纸
If you're interested in that, I think it's really cool. I'll show you that here in a bit.
感兴趣的话 我感觉还挺酷的 我一会就给大家看
Anyway, on with the talk.
好 看演讲吧
We now get to get to our closing keynote for the day.
我们现在开始今天的闭幕主题演讲
We are really honored and pleased to have this speaker with us.
非常荣幸 非常开心能邀请到这位演讲者
He's no stranger talking to large audiences.
大伙可能对他并不陌生
Destin Sandlin is a husband, father, and aerospace engineer known for his educational video series, Smarter Every Day.
Destin Sandlin 一位丈夫 一位父亲 一位航天工程师 油管著名频道"天天大聪明"的频道主
He's also a current UAH student.
当然 他现在也是阿拉巴马大学亨茨维尔分校的学生
So, Destin, I turn it over to you for you to talk. Thanks.
那么 Destin 讲台交给您 谢谢
Thank you. Hello.
谢谢 大家好
I'm seeing people I know. That's always good.
看到我认识的人感觉真好啊
My name is Destin, and when you leave here, what I'm hoping is that
我叫Destin 我希望大家听完我的演讲 大家能做到:
you'll look at the mission differently. In a world of talkers, you'll be a thinker and a doer and ask the hard questions.
1 用不同角度看待任务 2 少说多想多做 3 会问刁钻的问题
I've... Well, let's just do this.
那么我们开始吧
Who is this dude? It's a thing we do in Alabama.
台上这人谁啊? 我们阿拉巴马人都这样
I know you guys from all over the place.
我知道在座各位来自各地
Here in Alabama, we like to just... Can you hear me?
我们阿拉巴马人都……能听清吗?
Is this good? Okay.
声音还行吧? 好
Here in Alabama, we're just low key, rednecks.
我们阿拉巴马人都是帮低调的红脖子
You know that about us by now.
你们应该感觉到了吧
I'll just go through who I am.
所以我先介绍下我自己
I grew up across the river and just a Redneck kid.
我在河对岸长大 就是个红脖子小屁孩
That's me and my big dog, Thunder. My dad's over there.
图中是我 和我的大狗 Thunder 我父亲在台下
Dad, you can come up here and sit down if you want.
嘿老爹 你愿意的话可以过来坐下
You're okay? Yeah, dad's here.
站那行吗? 行 那是我父亲
Yeah, dad's awesome. [Audience applaudes]
我爹老厉害了 [观众掌声]
I grew up just a normal kid, and my grandfather, my dad's dad, worked at this little outfit called the Army Ballistic Missile Agency.
我只是一个普通小孩 我的祖父 也就是我老爹的父亲 曾在一个叫陆军弹道导弹局的小机构工作
Have you ever heard of it? Yeah, you heard of it? Yeah, it's pretty good.
听过那单位吗? 听过? 嗯 挺牛的
His name was Pryor Wilson Sandlin, [Audience laughs] Why do people always laugh when I show this slide?
他叫Pryor Wilson Sandlin [观众笑声] 为什么观众看这PPT总笑啊
Every time I show my grandfather. They're like, Ha ha ha.
每次我放我爷爷照片 下面总有人在笑
I was like, I don't understand. This is how I grew up. It's a culture thing, I guess.
搞不懂 我就是这样长大的啦 可能这就是文化吧
But my grandfather, same guy that taught me how to shoot a squirrel out of a tree, a guy that taught me all kinds of stuff...
我的祖父 那个教我如何射树上松鼠的人 一个教我各种东西的人
I mean, he taught me about science and he would take me outside and he would show me stuff.
他教了我科学知识 他带我出去 带我看各种东西
I remember Granddaddy didn't, I don't know if you remember this dad, but Granddaddy didn't tell me he loved me.
我记得爷爷没有 不知道爹你是否有印象 但爷爷从没跟我说过他爱我
He didn't say that.
他从来没说过
He said, "Boy, I love you to the Comet Belt."
他说的是"小子 老子爱你爱到彗星带"
I was like, What the heck does that mean? I don't know what that means.
我当时就想 这什么土味情话 我根本听不懂
Then years later, I was sitting here in the halls of UAH, pencil-whipping some stuff, and I was calculating the Delta V requirements to go to Mars.
多年后 我坐在大学课堂里 用铅笔写写画画 计算去火星所需的速度增量
I was like, You know? Not only is it probable or possible that we're going to go to Mars, it's going to happen.
我突然想到 我们去火星不仅是有可能的 而且一定能做到
He loves me out beyond that. I know this is the asteroid belt, not the comet belt.
他对我的爱比火星还远 当然了这是小行星带 不是彗星带
I have to say this because you guys are smart.
在你们这帮大佬面前我用词得准确
But granddaddy used to say things like that.
但我爷爷当年就是这样说的
The same person that made me feel really, really small and made me want to outwit a squirrel, was the same guy that made me think about how big the universe was.
就是这个让我觉得自己非常渺小的人 教我逮松鼠的人 同时也让我思考这个宇宙有多么浩瀚
It's just how we grew up here in Alabama. It's great. I love it.
我就是这样在阿拉巴马长大的 这里很棒 我爱这里
I went to University of Alabama.
我后来读的阿拉巴马大学
I learned a lot from Darryl Sandlin right there who worked on the James Webb Space Telescope.
跟我父亲Darryl Sandlin学到了很多 他曾为詹姆斯·韦布空间望远镜工作
That's a picture of dad when he was doing metrology on the SunShields for the James Webb Space Telescope.
右边的图是他在为JWST的太阳遮罩进行形状测量工作
Really cool stuff.
非常酷的工作
Dad used to moonlight as a CMM operator and programmer, and he used to teach me stuff about coordinate transformations before I knew what algebra was.
我爹以前兼职做坐标测量机操作员和程序员 我还没学代数的时候 他就教我坐标变换了
I had a really neat upbringing.
我的成长经历确实还挺奇妙
I had internships at the University of Alabama. I worked at Eaton, aerospace.
读大学时我曾在伊顿宇航实习过
The cool thing about that is the test cell next to me, I was working on the Joint Strike Fighters fuel pump, which was also the hydraulic pump, really neat thing.
最酷的是我旁边的试验室 我当时正在研究联合打击战斗机的燃料泵 也是液压泵 很酷的东西
I used to test lubricity on that thing.
我曾经用它来测试润滑性
But in the cell right next to me was the SR-71 fuel pump test cell.
但就在我隔壁 曾经是SR-71燃料泵的试验室
It was designed to explode.
试验室就是用来炸的
They told me, they're in Jackson, Mississippi, they said, Yeah.
他们跟我讲 之前在密西西比的杰克逊
These dudes showed up and they're like, All right, we need a fuel pump that needs to do this flow rate and this pressure.
那帮人突然出现 上来就说要造一个燃料泵 多大流量 多大压强
The Mississippi boys were like, Nothing needs a fuel pump like that.
密西西比那帮人答复说"没听说过啥东西需要这样的泵"
They're like, Build it. [Audience Laughs]
然后他们说"别废话 造" [观众笑声]
That's the coolest story ever.
这故事太牛了
Anyway, I also worked at Little Debbie Snack Cakes,
我后来还在Debbie蛋糕厂实习过
basically the same level of, Why are you laughing at me?
技术难度差不多和……你们在笑啥?
Little Debbie is awesome.
Debbie蛋糕老牛逼了好吧
Let me tell you about Little Debbie.
我来跟你讲讲有多牛逼
Imagine this is a sheet of zebra cakes right here. It's moving along.
想象着有一排斑马蛋糕(zebra cake)的胚子 沿着生产线往前走
You have a double guillotine striking that thing as it moves along. That's great.
有两个裁切机给它们分块 很正常对吧
How do you get the chocolate drizzle on there?
蛋糕上面的巧克力条纹怎么做?
You just flip on this little switch and the little motor starts turning and the chocolate drizzle starts coming out and you get a sign wave on top of your cakes.
只要按下开关 电机就会带动巧克力酱喷嘴开始在蛋糕上画正弦波图案
But wait, there's more.
但这还没完
Flip another mechanical lever, you throw in the cosine, the other, you get it out of phase, it makes a circle.
拉下另一个操纵杆 正弦变余弦 你懂吧 错开个相位 机器就开始画圆
That's how they do the fancy cakes. They do zebra cakes and fancy cakes on the same line. It's incredible.[Audience Laughs]
斑马蛋糕上面是波浪图案 fancy蛋糕是很多交错的圆形图案
I'm wasting time. Let's keep going.
跑题了 我们继续
That was where I met my wife. Check this out, isn't she hot? [Audience Laughs]
这是我遇见我老婆的地方 怎么样 漂亮吧? [观众笑声]
My wife's really pretty too. You see my wife? She's great.
我老婆很漂亮吧 她很厉害
My wife and I, we have four kids and we love them and we think we're going to keep them.
我和我老婆生了四个孩子 我都挺稀罕的 养着吧就
Right here, this is my upbringing as a professional. I worked across the interstate here in a place called Redstone Test Center.
然后是我的职业经历 我以前在州公路对面的红石测试中心工作
The thing think on the left is a component for something called an active protection system.
左边的东西叫主动防护系统
We were trying to defeat rocket-propelled Grenades as they were fired at vehicles in Iraq and Afghanistan.
在伊拉克和阿富汗 我们想用它击毁向载具发射的RPG
I spent a lot of time on that.
我在这上花了很多时间
Maybe in 25 years, we can talk about that. But it's really cool.
可能25年后我们就能聊聊这个东西了 真的很酷
On the right, I worked missiles for a long time.
我研究导弹研究了很久
On the right, I went after a while and I was like, I'm going to go work on aircraft because I don't know aircraft.
后来我走了 当时想研究飞机 因为当时我还完全不懂飞机
I can't speak that language. I learned a lot there.
完全不懂那方面 我后来学到了很多
The cool thing about ATEC, Army Test Evaluation Command, we were in the developmental test command.
在美国陆军测试与评估司令部的时候 我当时在研发测试部门
We were helping acquire material for the army, material that would be used by soldiers.
我们当时帮军队采购物资 给士兵们使用的物资
Human rating of products was huge.
与人相关的产品 评级是相当严格的
I had to go through what's called the Defense Acquisition University. I get what it's like to human rate a product. It's a big deal.
我当时去了国防军需大学 我学到了与人相关的产品是多么严肃的事情
I'm just giving you that to say like, Yeah, you tip gaha, funny.
我只是想让大家知道 哈 你也懂点我们这行有多严肃吧
Also, a little bit of experience in the field here.
我对这个领域也确实有点了解
This is a cool thing.
还挺酷的
This is what we would call at the range Tuesday.
接下来是 我们一般叫 "测试场星期二"
Three, two, one, fire.
3 2 1 发射
A lot of people don't know, we test Javelin here.
很多人不知道 我们就在这测试标枪导弹的
I remember a very specific moment. We had just blown up a Russian tank.
有个场景我印象很深 我们刚炸了一个俄制坦克
I remember the smell. I just remember a lot of things.
我还记得那个味道 我记得当时很多事情
We've gone down and I'm living my best life, scoring the target, looking at the shape charge penetration in the hole.
当时还是我最好的时光 我们过去给目标打分 观察弹孔的侵彻
I look at Tracy Williams, who's a Vietnam veteran, who helped develop Javelin for when it was called All Zem, if you know about that.
我看着Tracy Williams 他是个越战老兵 他曾经参与研发标枪导弹 那时候还叫"All Zem" 不知道大伙听过没
He helped develop it. He fought in the Vietnam War.
他辅佐研发了这款导弹 他参加过越战
We're driving back up that road right there, Center Line Road, Test Area One.
我们当时往回开 1号测试场 中央路上
I look at Tracy and I said, Tracy, what are we doing?
我看着Tracy说 老哥 咱们到底在干嘛?
What are we even doing? He's like, What do you mean?
我们做这些是在干嘛? 给他问蒙了 问我啥意思
I was like, Dude, we can destroy a tank.
我说 我们都能摧毁坦克了
It's unbelievable how good we are at this. We can blow up tanks and throw the turret.
这摧毁效果也太好了 我们能直接把坦克炸烂 掀了炮塔
There is never going to be another land war in Europe with tanks.
以后欧洲陆地战场上可能再也不会出现坦克了
This is dumb. Nobody's ever going to do this.
这太蠢了 没人敢上的
Young buck, right? I got it figured out. [Audience Laughs]
Too Young Too Simple吧? 我现在知道了 [观众笑声]
I look at the gray beard, Tracy says, I've seen a lot of things.
我看着Tracy的灰胡子 他说 我遇到过不少事
You never know. You never know, young man. Keep driving.
世事难料 世事难料呀 小伙子 好好开车吧
Fast forward to recently, right?
直到现在
I think about that conversation a lot.
那段对话我思考了很久
I had it figured out.
我现在想清楚了
We got the new technology.
我们现在有了新技术
There will never be these old problems coming back.
这些老毛病再也不会出现了
Man, I think about that a lot.
天啊 我真的想了很多
I used to goof around at night making stuff in the garage.
我晚上经常在车库里瞎鼓捣
This is the first photo I ever took of a bullet striking a match. I was really excited about that.
这是我拍的第一张子弹擦过火柴棒的照片 老高兴了当时
Then one day, I did something silly.
有一天我干了件特蠢的事情
I got my dad a Father's Day present.
我送了我父亲一个父亲节礼物
I don't know if the audio is working here, but we're just going to roll with it.
我不知道声音怎么样 就这样播放吧
I uploaded this.
这视频我还上传了
Hey, it's me, Destin. Can you hear that at all?
"大家好 我是Destin" 大家能听到吗?
I got my dad a present for Father's Day, and this got weird.
"我为我父亲准备了节日礼物 有点奇怪"
I uploaded this to the internet, and I was taking guidance and control classes here.
我把这个视频上传到了网上 我当时在上制导与控制的课程
I got him a chicken. It's a chicken.
我送了他一只鸡 "这是一只鸡"
I got my dad a chicken.
"我给他准备了一只鸡"
I started looking at it, and I was like, there's some GNC stuff going on here.
GNC: 制导导航与控制
It knows where its head is.
它知道自己的头在哪里
As it moves, somehow there's a control loop here.
我移动鸡身的时候 它就好像有个闭环控制一样
Then this happens.
然后就是这样
The motion is going so you can compensate for it.
"发生运动时 可以对其进行补偿"
The chickens are really good at this. I'll show you. Watch his head stay totally stationary. [Audience Laughs]
"鸡很擅长这件事 大家看 它的头可以保持不动"
You guys are super nerdy, so I know where your brain's going right now. You're going to the pigeon guided bomb in the world.
[观众笑声] 在座的各位都很聪明 我知道你们在想啥 二战的鸽子导弹是吧
I know what you're thinking. You're great, you're smart.
我猜到你们在想什么了 大伙那么聪明
But this is not what I was thinking.
但我当时想的不是这个
In the moment, I was like, I'm going to upload this to the internet because it's amazing.
我当时想的是 这么牛逼 我要把视频传到网上
This is amazing because there is clearly a closed loop control system here that [Audience Laughs] appears to be optically coupled to this chicken. I'm back driving it.
有多神奇 鸡显然有一个 通过光学耦合的闭环控制系统 [观众笑声]
You know why chickens do this, by the way? Do you know this?
话说你们知道鸡为什么会这样吗? 大家知道吗?
This is the smartest room I've ever talked to. Nobody knows this.
你们听过我演讲的最聪明的人了 没人知道吗?
Okay, so basically there's this thing called the vestibula ocular reflex.
有一个词叫"前庭眼反射"(vestibulo-ocular reflex)
Do you know about it? Everybody look at my hand.
大家听过吗? 没听过的话看我的手
I'm going to move my hand. Track my hand.
我左右挥挥手 你们眼睛盯着我的手
Okay, birds have a hard time doing that.
对于鸟类来说这件事很难
What they do is they lock their head and that's the reference frame, and then they walk under it and it ends up looking like this.
所以鸟类会锁定头部位置 作为参考系往前走几步 最后结果就是这样
They'll walk and then they'll walk under it. They'll throw their head, and it makes sense now?
走一步 挪一下脑袋 再走一步 再挪一下脑袋 懂了吧?
That's what they do.
鸟类是这样解决的
Yeah, so when whoops! [Audience Laughs] that's great.
所以当……我靠 [观众笑声] 行吧
Basically, what's happening is I'm uploading this to the internet and I'm like, Man, I'm in the thinky place.
所以我当时上传这个视频初衷是 哇 我真的在思考这件事
I'm really smart and I'm proud of myself for how smart I am.
我感觉我好聪明呀 我真的很自豪
Then what does the internet do with this?
但互联网是如何回应我的?
Hey, look at this red neck playing with a chicken on the internet.
"近日 一位外国小哥把他家一只鸡的视频发到了网上"
He'll take that thing and he'll move it like this and that head stays right there.
"他移动鸡的时候 鸡的脑袋竟然保持不动"
I'm like, No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no. No, no, no. I'm smart, I promise.
我当时心想"别别别别别别别这样 我不是营销号 真的"
I'm trying to be smart about this.
我想好好解释这个事情
They're like, No, man, that chicken wiggle so weird.
但网友们还是"哇这只鸡好神奇啊"
I was like, Not like this.
我当时就"不!是!这!样!"
But then after that, something happened.
但在这之后 又发生了些事情
I got to think about things. This grew into Smarter Every Day.
我开始思考各种事情 这个习惯也带入了"天天大聪明"这个频道
The reason it grew into Smarter Every Day is my dad made me take a business minor class, honestly, that was part of it.
之所以发展成这个频道 是因为我父亲让我辅修一门商业课程 说实话 这也是部分原因
But one of the things I did is I reevaluated how I looked at how I communicate with people.
但我做的其中一件事是 我重新评估了自己与人沟通的方式
Basically, I decided, You know what I'm going to do? I'm going to do this.
简单来讲 我决定……我接下来要这样
I'm going to take my videos, which I create called PennyWhistle Productions,
我的视频工作室名叫PennyWhistle制片
I'm going to brand it because dad made me take a marketing class.
我要给它起个响亮的名字 因为我父亲让我上过市场营销课
I'm going to call it Smarter Every Day.
我要叫它"天天大聪明"
I'm going to focus on quality over quantity, and I just basically engineered it. That's all I did.
我要注重质量而不是数量 我基本上就是这样设计的
And this happened. This is another thing I did.
然后是我做的另一件事
I said, Every video I make, I'm going to be deliberate about how I execute the video.
我做的每一个视频 都要慎重考虑如何安排内容
I'm going to start the video with incredibly high personality. It's going to be fun.
视频的开头一定要充满个性 一定要有趣
I'm going to tell you about chickens and you're going to like it because chickens.
我一开始就抱上来一只鸡 大伙肯定喜欢 这是只鸡呀
Then slowly I'm going to ramp down the personality over time and I'll ramp up the topical complexity.
然后随着时间的推移 我会慢慢减弱个性 提高内容的复杂性
When you ramp up that topical complexity, then people walk up that mountain with you
当你慢慢提高内容复杂度时 观众会跟你一起啃这个内容
because it's not like, Hey, zero to a hundred instantly.
因为这个内容不是一瞬间灌输给大家的
Let's talk about the sheer, let's talk about mohr's circle right now.
莫尔圆(Mohr's circle) 一种用二维方式表示柯西应力张量转换关系的图
No, we're just going to slowly ramp up the mountain together.
不 我们要一起慢慢克服难题
Then towards the end of the interaction, I ramp down before people get bored and scared.
然后在内容的结尾 我会在大家感到无聊或者被公式吓晕前降低内容的复杂度
Kind of like right now, it's getting weird right here.
有点像现在的情况 气氛开始奇怪了
I ramp it down and then we land the plane. I'm going to do that with my videos.
我会慢慢降低难度 让视频平稳着陆 我的视频都是这样操作的
And it worked. It worked very, very well.
很有用 非常非常有用
That was really, really cool.
感觉很酷吧
If only going to the moon were that easy.
要是去月球也这么简单就好了
Let's just get a plan. Let's write it down. Let's award some contracts and let's do it.
做好计划 写下来 前几个合约 开干!
If only your job were that easy.
你们的工作要是这么简单该多好
Why is it so difficult to do what you do?
大家做的事情为什么如此困难?
My assumption here is that I'm talking to a room full of policymakers,
我的假设是 我正在给满屋子的决策者演讲
intelligent people that are going to shape the future of human space flight. Is that correct? [crickets]
你们都是聪明人 你们将决定人类太空飞行的未来 我说的对吧?
Somebody talk to me.
给个回话
Engineers, program managers.
工程师们 项目经理们
Yeah, this is the event where you get to put on literally your fancy pants and come hang out together, right?
大伙今天一身西装革履 群贤毕至 不就是为了这个吗?
Yeah, I heard about the ball or whatever you guys did. Very nice. [Audience Laughs]
当然我听说还有舞会什么的 挺牛的 [观众笑声]
One of the reasons why things get difficult is politics.
事情变得困难的原因之一 是政治
Politics, I learned this firsthand.
政治 我亲身体会过
You remember where this started, by the way, the chicken thing?
还记得一切的开始吗? 那只鸡
Well, somehow it ended up here.
我一路走到了这里
I don't know how that happened. Somehow it ended up here.
我也不知道我怎么做到的 反正就是见到奥巴马了
What I learned in this moment is here in Huntsville, I was like, Hey, I'm going to go talk to the President.
我从中学到的东西……当时我在亨茨维尔 我说"哥们 我要去和总统对话了"
Hey, John, what do you think I should ask the President? I get three questions. What should I ask?
"John 你觉得我能问点啥? 我能问三个问题"
John's over there. [In Southern Accent] He's like, I'll tell you what I'd tell him.
John喝了口 操着南方口音回答说"我要是你就这么说"
I'm like, Yeah, what is that?
我说"洗耳恭听"
[Accent again] He ain't going to take my guns. [Audience Laughs]
[南方口音] "休想禁掉我手里的枪" [观众笑声]
I'm like, John, here's the deal, buddy. This is literally going to happen. I'm literally going to talk to the President.
我当时说"John 我没跟你开玩笑 我真的要去对话总统"
I don't think I'm going to win friends and influence people if I do that.
我不是说我这样做会交到新朋友或者影响别人
We got to like, That's not going to work.
这样行不通的
Politics, you got to communicate.
政治 你得多多沟通
One of the things I did, and I'm going to burn this because of time too.
我做的其中一件事 时间关系 这段我就不放了
One of the things I did is I talked to him about political discourse.
我做的一件事就是和他谈论政治言论
You know what? I'm not burning it.
算了 还是放吧
Let's go. Let's see.
我们看一下这段吧
I decided to ask the first question on how he gets smarter on topics he might not be the expert on.
我问的第一个问题是他如何在自己可能不擅长的话题上变得更聪明
It was an interesting answer because it's clear that he's changed his methods over the course of his presidency.
回答很有趣 因为他担任总统期间 他很明显改变了自己的方法
As he was answering this question, it was pretty clear to me that he was in interview mode.
回答这个问题时 我明显感觉他进入了采访模式
His body language was a little rigid.
他的肢体语言有些僵硬
Now, keep in mind that at this point, the president still doesn't know what interviewer I'm going to be.
别忘了 此时总统还不知道我是什么样的采访者
For all he knows, I could be hostile.
按他的认知 我有可能是带有敌意的
What happened next was a moment I will never forget.
而接下来发生的事情 我永远不会忘记
I knew before he did that we were both on the same wavelength, and I really wanted to let him know that.
我知道我们的想法其实是一致的 我也很想让他知道这一点
After all, I had listened to him already for 10 hours via audiobook.
毕竟我听了10小时他的有声书
If you watch the President's face, you can see the exact moment that we connect.
如果你仔细观察总统的表情 就会发现我们之间产生共鸣的那一瞬
And that, I think, is pretty consistent with how scientists approach problems in general.
"我认为 这与一般科学家处理问题的方式非常一致"
Now, I actually knew that about you because I've listened to your audiobooks.
"我知道您是这样想的 因为我听过您的有声书"
And in Dreams of My Father, it ended with the 2004 Democratic National Convention speech.
"在《我父亲的梦想》中 结尾是2004年民主党全国代表大会的演讲"
Did you see it? Let's back it up and watch his body language.
发现了吗? 我们倒回去看他的肢体语言
He's a little guarded and then the connection. Isn't that cool?
他开始时有点戒备 然后突然我们之间隔阂就消失了 很酷吧?
It's the exact moment that this quit being an interview and became a fun, intelligent conversation between two individuals who want the best for each other.
在那一刻 这不再是一次采访 而是一次有趣的 智慧的对话 两个人都为对方着想
It was a really cool moment. And I won't forget it.
这一刻真的很酷 我不会忘记的
Okay, so the President went on to explain some really interesting things, and he talked about negative feedback
总统接着解释了一些非常有趣的事情 谈到了负反馈
and how we as a society have lost the ability to provide negative feedback to each other.
以及我们这个社会是如何失去彼此提供负反馈的能力的
Because why? [Zero response from audience...]
因为……因为什么呢? [全场寂静]
Yeah, you guys are... This is the thing.
你看 你们就…… 这就是我想说的
You're scared to even talk right now. [Audience Laughs]
你们现在都不敢把话讲出来 [观众笑声]
I'm not joking.
我没开玩笑
You're terrified to talk right now.
你们现在不敢讲话
That's a problem. That's a problem.
这是个问题 这是一个问题
You know the truth and you're afraid to say it.
你们知道事实如何 但不敢讲出来
I'm Destin, have a good day.
我是Destin 谢谢大家——
No, the deal is we know things and we're afraid to say it.
关键是 我们直到事实 但不敢讲
Why is that? Because we know the other side is going to fight or we might get canceled or whatever is happening today in your office.
为什么会这样? 因为我们知道可能会发生矛盾 可能会被反驳 各种上班时可能发生的糟心事
I totally get it.
我完全理解
But we're engineers, right?
但我们是工程师啊! 对吧!
Engineers know what this is, don't they?
工程师们知道这是什么 对吧?
Young engineers on the front row. What is this?
前排年轻的工程师们 这是什么呀?
[Audience memeber] PID! PID control loop.
[观众回答]"PID"  对 PID闭环控制
Rock and roll. That's what I'm talking about.
上道了啊 我说的就是这个
What's an important part of the PID control loop?
PID闭环控制中的关键是什么?
Let's ignore the letters. Let's go up here to the little summation symbol on the top right.
咱甭管字母 看到右上角有个绿色的小加号吗?
You got a plus and a minus. What does that mean? [Audience] Feedback.
一个加号一个减号 什么意思啊?  [观众回答] 反馈
Feedback. Right.
反馈 没错
Feedback is important to any engineer.
反馈对每个工程师来说都非常重要
If you have only positive feedback in the system, what happens to it?
如果系统里只有正反馈 会怎么样啊?
It goes unstable.
会不稳定
Is this political science?
这是什么政治学吗?
This is math, right?
不 这是数学 对吧
It also works with political science.
当然政治学里也说得通
But it's really interesting. If you don't have positive and negative feedback in any system, it goes unstable and chaotic and things explode and break and it's bad, right?
但这真的很有意思 系统中没有正负反馈 就会变得不稳定 变得混乱 结果就是一团乱麻 对吧?
We know this to be true because whatever your degree is.
无论你的学位是什么 这都是真的
I think it's important for negative feedback. I'm grateful that I learned that.
我觉得负反馈是很重要的 我很高兴我学到了这点
I also asked the President about his plans for deep space exploration at the time.
我当时还问了总统他的深空探索计划
Personally, I'm going to say this because it's an opinion I have and I'm allowed to have opinions.
就我个人而言 我要这么说是因为这是我的观点 我可以有自己的观点
I was unsatisfied with his answer at the time.
我当时对他的回答并不满意
Now, that's a big deal because as people that work with NASA, you're an executive branch thing, right?
这很重要 因为作为与NASA合作的人 你要在行政方面负责 对吧?
That stability in your direction is very, very difficult. It's hard.
把握前进方向的稳定 是非常非常困难的 非常难
Congratulations, you guys have successfully navigated that. You have.
恭喜你们 你们成功把握了这个方向 你们做到了
There's a lot of reasons you navigated that.
你们的方向性有多种表现
Artemis branding was a big part of that.
阿尔忒弥斯计划的口号就是很好的体现
Kind of like PennyWhistle Productions flipping it to Smarter Every Day.
就像我之前PennyWhistle制片改名叫"天天大聪明"一样
It's great. I love how nervous you guys are.
太棒了 我太喜欢看你们紧张的表情了
This is great. This is more fun for me than it is you.
真的 我感觉这对我来说比对你们来说更有意思
Everybody, I'm seeing this, I'm seeing this, I'm seeing this. This is so good.
在座的各位 姿势表情有这样的 有这样的 有这样的 太逗了
We're going, right?
我们要出发 对吧?
I've seen the video.
av54708574
We are going.
我们要出发!
I've heard people make fun of the video, but I think it's a pretty good video.
我看过别人恶搞过那个视频 但我还是很喜欢它
But there's this thing, in the back of all your heads, at least it would be for me.
但有一件事 你们应该清楚 至少我很清楚
The beautiful thing about this is I get to leave and I'm not in anybody's food chain in the room. That's the coolest thing about this.
对我来讲一件好事就是 我今天讲完抬屁股就可以走了 我和在座各位都没什么利害关系
There's a scoreboard that exists and the scoreboard looks like this.
话说回来 有那么一个计分板 长这样
My buddy Michael made this today.
我哥们Michael今天做了这张图
It's a scoreboard, Lunar Landings, Apollo era engineers and infrastructure. Six Lunar landings; Artemis, zero.
这是个计分板 比分是登月次数 阿波罗时代的工程师与设施6分 阿尔忒弥斯计划0分
That's pretty cool, isn't it? That's pretty cool. We made that. I was like, I don't think that'll work. We made that.
还挺酷的吧? 挺酷的 我没想到做出来效果这么好
Let's look at this. Let's look at this. They did it, right?
我们看看这张图 阿波罗做到了 对吧?
They've got points on the board. They did it.
他们有6分呢 他们做到了
We're going to do it, right?
我们也要做到 对吧?
We're going?
我们要出发吗?
We're going, yeah. Okay, let's look at how they did it.
要出发 好 我们看看他们怎么做到的
This is a really cool graphic.
这张图示真的很棒
This is the mission for Apollo.
介绍的是阿波罗登月任务流程
Left Earth, circularized left, went out to LLO, went down, ascent stage, come back up.
从地球起飞 圆化轨道 飞离地球 来到近月轨道 下降 再从月球起飞
There's some Rendezvous action in there. Come home, right?
然后交会对接 然后返回地球 对吧?
That's what they did.
他们是这样做的
Here's Artemis III. Let's look at this.
这是阿尔忒弥斯3号任务 看看咱们
Remember the part about saying the truth earlier?
还记得我刚刚说的 把真相说出来吗?
What do you guys think about this?
你们怎么看这个计划?
It's different. It's different.
"有区别"  "有区别"
A very wise, politically savvy engineer that I happen to know.
真是个聪明绝顶精通政治的工程师的高情商回答啊
It's different. It is different. Why is it different? Why is it different?
有区别 不一样了 为什么呢? 为什么不一样?
Okay, so let's zoom in on this one thing.
我们看图中这个部分
Again, I'm going to leave the room. I can do that.
我再强调一遍 我今天演讲完抬屁股就能撤
You have to deal with this.
做这项目的人是你们
This is the orbit around the moon. It's not a low lunar orbit.
这是届时的绕月轨道 它不是近月轨道
It's NRHO, Near Rectalinear Halo Orbit.
而是NRHO "近直线晕轨道"
Have you guys researched NRHO? Have you looked into it?
大家知道NRHO这条轨道吗? 大家有了解过吗?
Do you know why we're doing it? Do you know why we're doing NRHO?
知道为什么要这么做吗? 为什么选择了NRHO?
[Audience Member] Line of sight with the earth. Line of sight with the earth. Okay, so gateway.
[观众回答]"与地球保持视距通信"  视距通信 嗯 月球门户空间站
I know the reason. I know the reason. And you know the reason.
我知道原因 我知道 你们也知道
A lot of you know the reason. If you don't, you need to figure it out.
你们很多人知道原因 不知道的话你们也应该查查
Okay, so my tone when saying that is a little off.
我说到这里的时候声音变得很低
You probably have never heard Destin talk like that. Let me explain what's going on.
你们可能从来没看到我用这样的声音说话 我来解释一下发生了什么
There's a lot of people in the room, not all the people in the room,
演讲上有很多人 虽然不是全部的人
but a lot of people in the room understand that I am bringing up a truth that they've often wondered about.
不过研讨会上很多人知道 我问出了一个他们一直奇怪的问题
Why are we using NRHO, near rectalinear halo orbit?
为什么选择NRHO 为何选择近直线晕轨道?
Because that's a really big orbit that takes many days to get back to the moon,
这条轨道绕月一圈要好几天
whereas Apollo did low lunar orbit, which comes down really close to the surface of the moon. It's much more simple.
而阿波罗的近月轨道 非常靠近月球 明明更简单才对
So the reason we're doing this is because the Orion spacecraft does not have enough Delta-V to get down into low lunar orbit.
我们选择NRHO的原因是 猎户座飞船没有足够的速度增量前往近月轨道
It's just not how you would design the system if you were to design something for scratch.
你如果从零开始设计一套登月方案 肯定不会这样做
And so I'm saying the truth, and everybody in the room is like, he's saying things we don't normally talk about.
所以我把事实讲了出来 而房间里的每个人都觉得 这是他们碰都不能碰的话题
And so that's why the tone is a little off.
也因此 我当时声音放低了些
There's a lot of people in the room that this is resonating with, but that's what's happening.
研讨会上有很多人对此产生了共鸣 但这就是事实
Line of sight with the earth is one of the stated reasons.
与地球保持视距通信是原因之一
This was one of the charts that went into the decision-making process for NRHO.
图中的表格来自一个讲述为何会选择NRHO的文章
If you look over here, you'll see that for communication, I don't have a pointer, but you're smart, you can figure this out.
大家看右侧第二列 通信方面 我手里没有激光笔 但相信你们知道我在说哪里
We've got Earth access (Orion) lunar access to polar, low-lunar orbit,
这里有地球出发的猎户座飞船到达能力 近月极轨道到达能力
station keeping, crewed, spacecraft communication, and thermal.
轨道保持消耗 载人飞船通信能力 热环境控制需求
We're going to put gateway there.
假如把门户空间站放在这些轨道上
Contact with it via radio is important.
那么通信肯定是个重要问题
NRHO is… We're putting that there because we have to communicate with the crew, right?
选NRHO 因为我们要和上面的宇航员时刻保持通信对吧?
Right?
对吧?
I don't believe you.
我都迷茫了
All right, so another thing they said is… You know, if we do this,
行吧 另一个因素是 如果我们选择了NRHO
then we can get down to low lunar orbit in half a day, half a day burn.
我们可以在半天内转移到近月轨道 半天的点火
This is the port… This was a NASA paper I read.
这个表来自NASA发表的论文
It takes half a day to get from NRHO to low lunar orbit, right?
从NRHO到近月轨道需要半天时间 对吧?
[Audience is Silent]
[观众没人说话]
Right? Guys, are we going?
对不对? 大伙! 咱还去不去了?
You should know this.
你们应该知道答案的!
That's what I'm doing. I'm just going to tell you the trick.
这样 我提前给你们剧透一下我要干啥
I'm going to be the bad guy for a little bit, and then I'm going to come back around and I'm going to inspire you at the end.
前半部分我要演一段时间的反派 到演讲最后我再回来鼓励大家
But I just need to be the bad guy for a little bit, okay?
但我现在需要演一下反派 好吗?
Can you just roll with me on that?
所以大家能配合我的演出吗?
Here's the deal.
所以事情是这样的
This paper, which was used for justification to select NRHO,
这篇文章 内容是讲解为什么我们选择了NRHO
said it takes half a day to get from NRHO to LLO, right?
里面说从NRHO转移到近月轨道需要半天时间 对吗?
What's the period time of NRHO?
请问NRHO的轨道周期是多少?
It's a week, six and a half days, right?
近一周 六天半对吧?
What we're saying is we're in NRHO, the microphone is now the moon, we're in NRHO.
所以我们在NRHO上 假如这麦克风是月球 我们在NRHO
It's a very high elliptical looking, non-keptelurion orbit. It's a three-body orbit. By the way.
这条轨道很像细长的椭圆 但并不是椭圆轨道 因为这是一个三体问题的轨道
It's a complicated thing. It's a thing and it takes six and a half days to get back by the moon.
这条轨道其实很复杂 要花费六天半才能回到近月点
When you do it, you're screaming. You're going fast.
而且在近月点 你速度超级超级快
Yeah, it takes half a to get from NRHO to LLO if you're in the right phase.
NRHO转移到近月轨道确实只需要半天 但前提是你要在正确的相位上
Because if you'd go try to land, you're like, Oh, snap, we got to abort. We got a helium leak.
因为假如你要准备着陆了 你发现"我靠 取消着陆 氦气漏了"
Depending on how far down towards the lunar surface you went, you might not be able to catch the bus.
取决于你在近月轨道下降了多少 你很可能赶不上这圈轨道回空间站了
You might have to wait till it comes up back around.
你可能需要等下个周期才能回到空间站了
That should go in your mission planning.
这件事应该会出现在你们的任务规划中
That dictates all kinds of things. That dictates...
这决定了很多很多事情 决定了……
The man that taught me systems engineering is right there, Dr. Thomas. How are you doing?
教我系统工程的老师就在那边 Thomas博士 你好呀
He taught me systems engineering by talking about the transmission in his old truck.
他用他家的旧卡车的变速器教会了我系统工程
Is that thing running, by the way? [Dr. Thomas] Not yet. Not yet. [Audience Laughs]
顺便那玩意还能用吗?  [Thomas博士]"不能了"  不能了 [观众笑声]
It's kinda like... Well, never mind.
就好像……算了
Basically, you have to factor in everything. You have to factor in absolutely everything.
所以基本上 你们需要考虑所有情况 要考虑所有所有因素
When I understood this, I was like, Wait a second, are you telling me that it's possible that an astronaut could be on the surface of the moon?
当我明白这点的时候 我当时就在想: 等一下 是不是有可能 宇航员在月球上的时候……
Whether it's a medical thing or...
发生了一些医疗事件或者……
The astronauts are smart, they know that if there's a medical, incapacitated crew rescue mission, it's probably a body recovery.
宇航员们都很聪明 他们知道如果发生了医疗情况 乘员失能了 需要营救 那其实要回收的只有尸体了
They're not dumb people. They know the risk. They are smart.
他们不是傻子 他们知道这个风险 他们很聪明
If something like that happens, how do we get them off?
如果发生了类似的事情 我们怎么把他们从月球表面弄走?
In the answer is, is it a half-day? It's not. It's we have to wait.
答案是半天吗? 不是 我们只能干等着
Anyway, you need to know this.
所以你们需要清楚这点
Anyway, when I started reading this, I started saying whoever, yeah, they wanted NRO to work.
我一开始读这个文章的时候 我的感觉是 这谁啊一个劲想用这条轨道
I came in here a little pious, like I sound right now. Remember, I'm the bad guy right now. I'm going to turn it around.
我之前说好像这轨道有多难一样 别忘了我还在演反派 现在我要变回好人了
I came in really wanting to punch you guys for making this choice.
我一开始很想揍一顿决定这条轨道的人
Then I started looking at the whole system and I was like, Oh, Orion can't get to low lunar orbit.
然后我放眼整个系统 我才明白 哦 原来猎户座去不了近月轨道
We have to do this.
我们只能选这条轨道
It's not about communication.
这跟通信能力没关系
We can put communication on there to give us a green box to justify it.
我们可以搞个中继星 把这个框框变绿
But what this thing doesn't say is that orbit can't see the landing site. But 86% of the time.
不过表格里没说的是 这条轨道不能一直看到着陆区 只有86%的时间能看到
We're going to have a relay satellite no matter what. We're going to have a relay system.
不论如何我们都要搞个中继星的 中继系统怎么样都是必需的
Because what's 14% of six and a half days?
因为六天半的14%是多少?
It's about a day. There's a day that we're not going to be able to talk unless we have a relay satellite.
大约一天 如果没有中继星 我们之间会有一整天的时间无法沟通
I got to think about all this.
所以我调查了整个系统
I found this in a paper. I thought this was really, really interesting.
我发现了这个论文 发现非常非常有意思
Then I started trying to understand the architecture to get there.
然后我才慢慢了解我们登月的任务架构是什么样的
I did not understand until this week when I really thought I was going to embarrass myself in front of you guys
不怕你们笑话 我这周才知道这件事
and then decided to further embarrass myself in front of you guys, I didn't realize that in order to get the human lander to the moon,
更不怕你们笑话的是 我之前不知道 为了把载人登月器送上月球
we have to launch a bunch of additional rockets to tank up in low-earth orbit.
咱们还要射一大堆火箭 在近地轨道上在轨加注
I didn't know that.
我之前完全不知道
I'm like, Well, how many rockets do we have to do that with?
然后我就想 这要打多少发火箭?
They're like, Six.
他们轻描淡写道 "6发"
Then I start, because I know people, I started calling people.
我认识不少人嘛 我就开始挨个联系问问这个问题
I was like, Dude, really, how many rockets is it?
"朋友 你知道这要打多少发火箭吗?"
They're like, Well, boil off...
他们上来跟我讲什么"燃料蒸发"……
I was like, Some people were like, Well, it's looking like eight.
有的人回答说是"差不多8发吧?"
I was like, Eight rockets?
我说"夺少? 8发?"
We have to fire eight rockets to fire one rocket to the moon?
把一个火箭送去月球要打8发火箭?
Then they're like, I mean, that's what they're saying, but it's probably more like 12, really.
然后他们又说"他们这么说的啦 但也有可能需要12发"
Then I was like, I'm an engineer, I know how to do this stuff.
然后我说 "得了 我也是工程师 我会算"
I started to do a count for nominal schedule slip and boil off.
然后我开始计算 包含了正常的余量 以及燃料蒸发
This is how many rockets it's going to take to fuel up that thing to get it to the moon. [Audience Laughs]
送登月器去月球需要的火箭数量大概是这些——[观众笑声]
I've done the math. If you have any questions, I'm joking.
我认真算过了 你们有问题吗? ——其实我在开玩笑
Remember, I'm the bad guy. I'm going to turn around and be the good guy in a minute.
记得吗 我开始演反派了 我马上就变回好人 稍等
The question is, is this smart?
我要问的问题是 这样的计划明智吗?
Now is the time where people are scared to talk again.
现在大伙又开始不敢说话了
Not efficient. It's not efficient.
效率低 效率不高
In the bottom right, I've drawn a picture, I've picked a picture from the We are going video.
右下角 我放了张图 我从"我们要出发"那个视频中选了张图
That's how many rockets went to the moon and landed for Apollo, for all of Apollo.
这是送我们去过月球的几发火箭
I'll take you back to this chart.
然后你们再看看这张图
Okay, I've said enough.
我要说的就是这些
Is this the simplest solution?
这是最简单的解决方案吗?
Okay, so I should probably leave now. I'm Destin. So it.
好 我是不是该走为上计了? 我是Destin 谢谢大家——
Looks like I'm picking on number of rockets in the talk here.
看起来我是在拿火箭数量说事
I'm actually picking on communication.
但我其实想说的是"沟通"
So the thing that's interesting to me is that people in the audience did not know the number of rockets that were going to be used to refuel the Lander.
我觉得有意思的点是 研讨会上的人不知道我们要打多少发火箭为登月器加注燃料
That's a problem.
这才是问题所在
I was trying to be funny, and there were stakeholders in the room.
我想表现得幽默一点 因为会场有计划的参与者
When I said 12 rockets the way I did. They laughed.
我说到12发的时候 他们笑了
It's probably more like 12.
"更可能是大概12发吧" [观众笑声]
There were others that weren't laughing.
也有人没笑出来
Here's the deal. People didn't know the answer to this question.
事情重点是 他们不知道这个问题的答案
Shortly after delivering this talk, we saw an answer to this question. This article came out.
这次演讲结束后 我们看到了问题的答案 因为出现了这篇文章
Someone at NASA said it's going to take at least 15.
NASA的人说 需要至少15发
So we at least have a baseline now. We have a floor. It could be more than that. It's at least 15.
至少现在有个起步价了 肯定比它多 反正至少15发
We still don't know the answer to how many rockets that's going to take to fuel that thing up.
我们仍然不知道 给登月器加油需要多少发火箭
I would submit to you that that's a problem.
我认为这是一个问题
This is indicative of a communication problem.
这表明大家沟通出现了问题
The fact that we have this very complex architecture
面对如此复杂庞大的工程
and we don't know the exact answer to such a big question
我们却无法回答这样重要的一个问题
is pretty damning because if we don't know such a simple answer to a big question, what does that say about the little things?
这太糟了 如果这么重要的问题都没有一个简单的答案 那些细节怎么办?
When my grandfather was sipping coffee out of this mug down the road,
我祖父当年端着这杯子抿咖啡去上班的时候
they had quarterly reports on every little component of what was going on,
他们会有季度报告介绍每个部分的进展
down to the pressure transducers at some subcontractor at a small plant somewhere in America.
细节到说美国某个分包商小工厂的压力传感器
They knew what was going to happen because the more complex the system is, the more communication you need to make it work.
他们知道会发生什么 因为越复杂的系统 越需要高效的沟通才能实现
Saturn V quarterly film report number seven.
土星五号季度报告影片 编号7
I think there's a problem because right now we are two years out from this launch and we don't know the number of rockets.
视频发布于2023年11月 当时阿尔忒弥斯3号计划2025年发射
I don't think that means we're going to launch to this thing in two years.
我不是说我们要在两年内把它发射上去
I'm just saying it. That's where I'm at as an engineer.
我只是出于工程师身份说这个事
It's time to be honest. As engineers, we are not known to be effective communicators.
该坦白了 我们工程师确实不擅长高效沟通
That's just not a strong suit of an engineer.
工程师们都不太擅长这个
It is time to lay out and systematize the communication so that every organization that's involved knows far more information than they need.
现在是时候对沟通进行布局和系统化了 让每个相关组织都能拿到远超出他们的需要的信息
We have actual targets and dates that are actionable
我们要有一个明确的 可行的目标与日期
and they don't depend on a miracle in technological innovation occurring at some point on the Gantt chart.
不要寄希望于进度表上突然出现技术创新的奇迹
We actually have actionable things that have to happen in certain time frames.
我们有可行的事情能够在特定的时间内完成
And if something doesn't happen, a critical technology isn't development,
如果没完成 某项关键技术没有研发出来
we communicate that there's a schedule slip to everyone.
我们马上沟通 让大家知道 时间表上留出余量
The fact that it still says two years till this launch tells me that we have a communication issue,
他们说距离这次发射还有两年的时间 让我明白 这当中存在沟通问题
and I would like for that to be resolved by centralized leadership.
我希望通过集中力量强化沟通来解决这个问题
There, I said my thing.
这是我想说的
Okay, so at this point, you will see a shift in the tone of the talk.
此时 你们应该能注意到我说话语调的转变
I've laid out the problem.
我把问题摆在了眼前
Now I'm going to transition towards aspirational goals.
现在我要慢慢过渡到理想的目标
How do we get there?
怎么做呢?
And it's going to hinge a lot upon this. What made Apollo a success?
我主要会参考这本书 《阿波罗如何成功》
And you'll see me talk about that later here in the talk.
大家一会就能在演讲中看到我聊这本书
Remember what I said earlier about the importance of negative feedback.
还记得我之前说 负反馈的重要性吧
I am but a simple Redneck, Alabama, engineer.
我只是个普通的 阿拉巴马红脖子 工程师
But for real, here's the deal.
但说实话 事情是这样的
We're going.
我们要出发!
We've selected this architecture.
我们选择了这样的任务架构
So how do we make it work?
怎么让它能成功?
I'm going to accept the contracts are written.
我接受自己签下的那些合同了
We have European partners that are building the first node for Gateway.
我们欧洲的合作伙伴要生产门户空间站的第一个节点舱
I'm going to accept it right now. Let's say everybody in the room accepts it.
我接受了 假设大伙都接受了
We're going, we're going to be unified and we're going to make it happen.
我们要去月球 我们要联合起来 实现登月
Now, what do you do with that information? What do you do with that information?
那么知道这些后你要做什么? 你会怎么做?
I think the key is to learn lessons from the past.
我觉得关键是从过去学习经验
Who is this person? Joseph Shea.
这人是谁? Joseph Shea
He's a very, very important person.
这个人非常非常重要
This story, I'm about to tell you, is sad.
接下来我要讲的故事 很伤感
Joseph Shea is sitting in a meeting here in the '60s in a presentation.
图中是60年代Joseph Shea正在会议上演示
If you're in the airspace industry, you're in meetings all day long.
航空航天这个行业 基本天天都在开会
That's what you do. That's what this guy is doing right now.
这行业就这样 这哥们现在就是
Who are these people?
这些人又是谁?
Apollo 1.
阿波罗1号乘组
Yeah, there's a high school here in Huntsville named Grissom, after the gentleman on the left there.
对 亨茨维尔这里有所高中名叫Grissom 以左边那位命名的
These astronauts were getting ready for Apollo 1, and they knew there were problems with the capsule.
这些宇航员们正在为阿波罗1号做准备 他们知道飞船有一些问题
They knew this.
他们是知道的
The engineer team knew there were problems with the capsule. Everybody was working feverishly to figure it out.
工程师团队知道飞船有问题 每个人都在急头白脸地想办法
Everybody was trying to figure this out.
每个人 每个人都在想办法解决
Then on January 27th, 1967, a travesty happened.
然后在1967年1月27日……悲剧发生了
There was an accident on the pad.
发射台上发生了事故
The capsule burned because they were in a 100% oxygen environment, a flame started by Gus Grissom's seat.
因为内部100%纯氧的环境 火星点燃了Gus Grissom的座椅 烧毁了飞船
They died.
三人全部遇难
I remember being at a family get-together years ago.
我记得多年前的一次家庭聚会
My grandfather worked over at NASA, and I remember hearing the old timers talk about that fire with deep sadness and reverence.
我的祖父曾在NASA工作过 我记得听到老一辈人谈起那场大火时 都带着深深的悲伤和敬畏
It occurred to me that something changed about NASA in that moment.
我突然意识到 从那一刻起 NASA变了
It changed in the middle of Apollo. Things were going so fast, something changed.
就在阿波罗工程中间 仿佛一瞬间 发生了改变
As a joke, I did not know this, and I'm just telling you this not to bring the room down, but I just want you to know that this happened.
有意思的事情是——我之前不知道啊 我不是为了扫兴 我只是说这事发生了
As a joke, before at the end of one of the meetings, the Apollo astronauts, they talk to the photographer,
有意思的事情是 在这场会议结束时 阿波罗1号的宇航员们跟摄影师说
they're like, Hey, we got to do one more joke. We're going to play a joke on Shea.
我们开个玩笑吧 跟Shea开个玩笑
We want a picture of us with praying hands around our capsule.
我们想拍一张大家围在飞船周围祈祷的照片
We want to say, and they said down there, on the note, they said, It isn't that we don't trust you, Joe, but this time we've decided to go over your head.
我们想弄张纸条 上面写着 "不是我们不信任你 Shea 但这次我们打算越级上报了"
They were jokingly saying, We all know there's problems here, and we're just, man, we're not feeling good about it.
他们只是开玩笑地表达"我们知道有问题 我们只是预感不太好"
At the same time, to be clear, the Apollo astronauts, these gentlemen, they knew the risk
同时 要说明的是 这些宇航员 这些英雄们 他们知道风险的存在
and they didn't say something to the point where they're like, We got to fix it.
但他们从来没有说诸如"这个得解决"这些话
I don't know what happened. I don't know what happened.
我不知道发生么什么 我不知道
All I know is that an engineering mistake happened and it wasn't caught.
我只知道一个工程上的瑕疵出现了 而且没被发现
That's going to happen because we're humans and we're imperfect.
这种事情在所难免 我们是人类 我们不是完美的
But when that happened, what I do know is NASA changed, changed completely.
但当瑕疵出现的时候 我知道的是 NASA完全改变了他们的做法
The way they did things, like there were conversations that happened, and I'll go through that here in a minute.
他们做事的方式 就像曾经的对话一样 我稍后会讲
Here's something to think about.
我们来思考这样一件事
You guys like movies? Back to the future. It's pretty good one, right? Marty McFly, it's great.
你们喜欢电影《回到未来》吗? 很棒的电影 主角Marty McFly
One of the cool things about those time travel movies is
这些穿越主题电影很酷的一点是
they'll go back in time and they're like, Oh, man, I can't change things because of how crazily I will influence the timeline of the future.
他们穿越到过去 他们会"喔 我可不能改变这件事 因为这会极大改变未来走向"
If I move this bottle and the wrong person, whatever, I might not even be born.
如果我把这瓶水挪到这里 然后错误的人这样那样 我可能未来都不会出生
These little changes have monumental impacts.
这些小小的改动会产生巨大的影响
Primer By the way, a really good time travel movie, if you haven't watched it, Primer, really good.
中文名 初始者
You've never heard of it. Budget for that movie was 7,000 bucks. Watch Primer, it's amazing. Great plot.
没听过吧 这电影拍摄预算7000美元 快去看吧 强烈推荐
These time travel movies, they can teach us something.
这些时间穿越电影 其实教会我们一个道理
Why do we not realize that we have that much control over the future now?
为什么我们没意识到 现在能对未来产生如此巨大的影响呢?
Right now, you have that much control over the future as you're sitting there.
你们现在坐在这里 就已经对未来有相当大的控制权了!
Oh, man, if I were just to send this email and say this thing in a compelling way
天啊 如果我把这封邮件发出去 里面把事情说得夸张一点
and impact the way the program reviews go and the CDR is coming up,
在关键项目评审的时候影响项目审查
if I could just get them to understand that Eclus needs to blah, blah, blah,
如果我能让他们知道那个阀门应该怎样怎样
why don't we have that level of gravitas to what we think about now?
为什么我们不能这样严肃看待现在正在考虑的事情?
I just think that's cool, something to think about.
我觉得值得思考一下这件事
Has anyone ever heard of this document?
有人看过这个文件吗?
Don't raise your hand. Don't raise your hand.
不用举手 不用举手
Does everybody remember the scoreboard earlier?
还记得之前的计分板吗?
Okay, so if I'm not mistaken, this room is full of people that are industry leaders that are in charge of taking humans back to the moon.
如果我没搞错的话 参加这次研讨会的有很多行业领头人 会负责人类重返月球计划
Okay, in your head, don't raise your hand, in your head, answer the following question, have I read NASA SP 287?
好 在你们脑中回答这个问题 不用举手: 我读过"NASA SP287"文件吗?
The title of the document is what made Apollo a success?
文件的标题是 《阿波罗如何成功》
Have you read it?
你们读过吗?
And if you have not read it, I'm not joking about this,
如果你没读过 我没开玩笑
shame on you.
丢人!
Seriously.
真的
You have a whole generation of engineers that did the coolest thing engineering humans have ever done, and they gave you the playbook.
你们曾有整整一代工程师 做出了人类史上无出其右的工程壮举 然后他们给你们留下了剧本
They wrote it. All you got to do is read it.
他们全写下来了 你们只要读就行了
I've read it. I'm not even in your food chain. I don't even... I've read this thing.
我读过了 我都不是你们体制内的 我都不……我反正读过了
Granted, I read it really, really fast, so I could say I read it for effect, but I read it. [Audience Laughs]
当然 我读得非常非常快 你可以说我是为了装B 但反正咱读了 [观众笑声]
I made highlighting things in here. I want to go through some of this with you.
我上面还做标记了呢 我想给大家分享几条
Imagine the scoreboard. You've got the people that actually went to the moon.
想想那个计分板 你们曾经把人类送到过月球
If they handed you the playbook and they're like, Hey, this is how you do it.
他们把剧本交给你手里 告诉你 "给 照这样做就好"
This is the key.
这就是秘籍
Seems pretty important. This exists.
应该挺重要的吧 这东西真的存在
It's crazy that you don't know that if you don't know that this exists.
你要是不知道这东西的存在 可太离谱了
Okay, it's really fun to read, by the way.
不过读起来还是很有意思的
It's written by several people that were over different things like trajectory calculations. Jean Krantz writes a section.
整本书是由几个负责不同内容的人写的 比如Jean Krantz写了弹道计算的章节
It's a lot of really good stuff, but let's just read some of them.
里面相当多的精华 我们挑几段看看
Of course, the way we got this job done was with meetings. Big meetings, little meetings, hundreds of meetings. The thing we always tried to do in these meetings was to encourage everyone, no matter how shy, to speak out,
"当然 我们完成这项工作的方式就是开会 大会小会 数以百计的会议 在这些会议上 我们一直努力做的事情就是鼓励每个人 无论多么害羞 都能畅所欲言 希望(但并不总是)不会受到嘲笑 我们希望确保我们没有忽略任何合理的意见"
That's how you feel now.
你们现在就是这种感觉
But I don't know, a lot of people are scared to talk today.
我也说不好 我感觉现在太多人不敢讲话了
Seems like they might have had a little different culture.
可能他们文化不太一样
All right, so spacecraft design, I thought this was interesting.
下一段 航天器设计 我觉得这段挺有意思
It talks about how a spacecraft designing it, you have elements of missiles and aircraft.
这里讲的是航天器的设计 里面提到了导弹和航空器
I've never designed a spacecraft, but I've worked with both aircraft and missile design.
我没设计过航天器 但我搞过航空器和导弹的设计
I feel like I get that.
我感觉我能理解
It says, and this is key, please hear this, this is the key to how to build your spacecraft.
上面是这样说的 这是关键 请仔细听 这是制造航天器的关键
Build it simple and then double up on as many components or systems so that if one fails, the other will take over.
"建造尽量简单的系统 然后尽可能多地为部件或系统设计冗余 这样一旦其中一个故障 另一个就能接替 例如 不需要再生冷却的推力室 不需要点火源的双组元推进剂 三组燃料电池等等"
I was blown away to learn that the ascent stage in the current design does not use hypergolic propellants.
我知道我们现在登月器上升级不是双组元(接触自燃)推进剂时都惊了
That blew my mind.
震撼到我了
I was like, Wait, so we're going up there and we got to ignite this. I get it.
我当时就在想 我们要从月球起飞 要让发动机点火 好的
You want to use in situ and you want to do methane. I got it, I understand.
你想在太空点火 想用甲烷做燃料 我理解
But hypergols always work.
但接触自燃燃料永远都能用!
You make them touch and they go, Boom, that's how it works.
两者一接触 马上就燃烧 就这么简单
I just thought it was interesting. I was like, We're changing.
我觉得这很有意思 我感觉我们在做出改变
Is that good?
这样的改变好吗?
Why are we introducing complexity into a system?
为何我们要为系统引入更多的复杂度呢?
I thought that was really, really interesting.
我觉得这非常非常有意思
This was an amazing chart.
这个图表非常牛
This chart, the person that wrote this, this was in the first chapter, the guy that wrote this, or the lady that wrote this, I forget, George M. Lowe wrote this.
阿波罗任务能力积累 阿波罗4号/6号 土星五号开发与航天器再入 阿波罗5号 登月舱开发 阿波罗7号 指令舱与服务舱载人运行 阿波罗8号 指令舱与服务舱月球轨道运行 阿波罗9号 登月舱指令舱与服务舱近地轨道联合运行 阿波罗10号 登月舱指令舱与服务舱月球轨道联合运行 阿波罗11号 月球表面着陆与起飞
Do we know George Lowe? Is this good or bad? I don't know. I'm ignorant. That's good? Okay.
有认识George Lowe的吗? 我念得对吗? 我不知道 我不会念的 还行? 好
You can tell how ignorant I am.
你看我文化水平很低的
This is great. I'm a third-party observer. I could leave and you guys have to deal with what I said.
就该这样 我只是个第三者 我想走就走 你们还得干这活呢
All right, so George Lowe said this, this is how they planned out what missions they were going to do when.
George Lowe说 他们是这样安排何时执行什么任务的
They said too small a step would have involved the risk that is always inherent in manned space flight without any significant gain,
文中说: "步子迈太小 就会积累载人航天飞行固有的风险 而不会有任何重大收获 也不会在登月方面取得任何实质性进展 另一方面 如果步子迈太大 可能会超出系统的能力范围 风险也会变得过大 因为飞行操作的新要求超出了人们在现有时间内学习 练习和完善的能力"
Basically, you don't take baby steps,
简言之 别小碎步前进
you take significant steps because you actually have to go towards the goal and there will be risk involved,
你要迈一大步 这样你才能向着目标前进 而这也会带来风险
but you make sure that the risk isn't too big so that the engineers on the ground can't learn the lessons.
所以你还要保证风险不能太大 要让工程师们每次能有所收获
I thought that was brilliant. That's amazing. I've never read anything like that.
我觉得这太牛了 我从来没看过这样的想法
I've worked on developing vehicles and active protection systems and counter missile systems.
我以前研究过载具主动防御系统 反导系统
That was so succinct. It was amazing.
这个总结 高度凝练 太牛了
Then I looked at Artemis III,
然后我看了下阿尔忒弥斯3号任务
to be clear, this is after Artemis II, which is about to happen.
要说明 这是阿尔忒弥斯2号任务之后的 而2号任务就快来了
On Artemis III, in order for this to work, it starts, up at the beginning, it starts or anyway,
阿尔忒弥斯3号任务 想要完成的话 在最开始……我们要……
we've never done cryogenic refueling in orbit.
人类连在轨低温燃料加注都没进行过
Humans have not done that.
人类还没做到过
Am I wrong about that? Somebody correct me. Am I wrong about that?
我说错了吗? 可以纠正我 我没说错吧?
Okay, let that sink in. Humans have never done cryogenic refueling in orbit up to this point right now.
好 我再重复一遍 人类迄今为止 从未进行过低温燃料在轨加注
Make all the charts you want, but we need to take some steps.
所以赶紧列个计划表吧 我们得一步步来
I don't know how you guys are doing your programs, but I think this is very, very interesting.
你们想怎么计划我不知道 但我觉得这件事真的非常有意思
I think it's important for you guys to talk about this with authority because you're smart and you know things.
我觉得大家跟领导说出这些事情很重要 你们很聪明 你们都知道这些事情
All right, don't get fixated on technology demonstration. Focus on the mission.
好 下一条 不要纠结于技术演示 多着眼于任务本身
Focus on the mission. Focus on the mission.
着眼于任务本身 着眼于任务本身
I sound arrogant right now, don't I? Please understand. I'm trying to be the voice of the 60s engineers, at least that's what I'm going to tell myself.
我是不是听起来有点傲慢? 希望大家理解 我只是想假装自己是60年代的工程师 至少我是这样告诉我自己的
What is the mission?
那么 任务是什么?
Some really cool people. Really, really cool people.
这些非常优秀的人们 非常非常牛
These folks are awesome.
他们都是精英
If you've ever met any of them, you know they are legitimately awesome people. They really are.
如果你们见过他们 肯定清楚他们是精英中的精英 真的
My advice, and it's not my advice, it's through the generation of my grandfather, is keep it simple.
我的建议 实际上不是我的 是我爷爷那辈人的——越简单越好
As simple as you can make it and accomplish the mission, that's what we should be doing.
能多简单就多简单 能完成任务就行 这才是我们应该做的
We should make it as simple as possible.
我们应该越简单越好
If you go through the old Apollo books, have you ever looked at how they decided to get the Lunar Lander off the moon, the ascent stage?
如果你们看过之前阿波罗的手册 里面如何让登月舱上升级从月球表面起飞的部分
Like, it's crazy because it's awesome.
老牛逼了 真的
They're like, All right, so we're going to get the timing right and we're going to launch.
大概就是 "哎呀到点啦 该起飞了"
That doesn't work because things aren't whatevering. Here's what we're going to do. You can read this in the stuff.
然后没飞起来 出问题了 怎么办? 照着上面写的做
They say, All right, if all else fails, here's what you do.
上面是这样写的 "没关系 如果全出故障了 你这样办——"
Open the hatch, go around the back.
打开舱门 来到登月舱后面
There's these guillotines that connect the decent and the asset stage.
连接下降级与上升级的地方 有一个闸刀
You had to flip a switch and it would cut the guillotines.
你要手动拨动一个开关 然后释放闸刀
They would cut them loose and they would be disconnected and ready to hit the motor and go up.
咔嚓一下 斩断连接 就能启动发动机起飞了
If that didn't work for whatever reason, they wrote a procedure. They're like, All right, here's the deal.
如果闸刀因为故障失灵了 下面还有: "没关系 你这样办——"
Dude on the left or dude on the right. Whoever has the best integrity of their suit at the time, the least amount of leaks,
登月舱上的两个人 你们谁的宇航服最完整 泄漏最少
you're going to depressurize, you're going to get out of the spacecraft, you're going to go to the bottom of the spacecraft with bolt cutters.
减压 出舱 拿着螺栓切割器去飞船底部
It's awesome. It's great.
拿着……这可太牛了!
With bolt cutters, and you're going to cut the straps that are holding the ascend and the decent stage together.
用螺栓切割器 把固定上升级和下降级的条带剪短
That's like the sixth thing down.
这可能是大概第六层备份
They tried this, okay, that worked. What if it doesn't work? Okay, we're going to go to this.
他们试了这个方案 OK搞定 要是搞不定呢? 那我们试试这个方案
Okay, then we're going to go to this.
不行就再试试这个
They had redundancy after redundancy after redundancy after redundancy all the way down to the bolt cutters.
他们有备份中的备份中的备份 一路备份到可以直接去剪分离条带
Harrison Schmitt said there was one thing after this. I just want to know what that was. [Audience Laughs]
Harrison Schmitt: 美国地质学家、宇航员 第十二个踏上月球的人 微信开屏画面就是他拍的
What is that? That's amazing.
真的 这还怎么备份??? 惊了
Are we building that level of redundancy into today's systems?
我们今天的登月系统 有这种程度的冗余备份吗?
Go look at the documents. This is a real thing.
看看文件吧 这是真的要造的东西——
All right, so [Audience Laughs] PID control loop.
好 那么…… [观众笑声] PID闭环控制
Positive and negative feedback is important.
正负反馈很重要
As the engineers responsible for getting humans to the moon safely and returning them,
作为负责将人类安全送上月球并将他们带回地球的工程师
our friends, it is imperative that you provide negative feedback in situations that call for it, and you are not scared to do so.
你们必须在需要的情况下提供负反馈 而且你们不应该害怕这样做
If you lose your job for providing negative feedback, good on you.
如果你因为提供负反馈而丢了工作 这是好事
If it needed to be said and nobody said it, that would be the worst thing to live with.
最糟糕的事情是 该说的话却没人说
Make sure you're speaking up. Be bold, be courteous.
要敢于发声 恭敬大胆
Once a decision has been made, let's all get behind it and let's fight.
一旦做出决定 我们就团结起来 一起战斗
But at the same time, let's be smart.
但与此同时 保持智慧
Other things that we have the architecture we have, let's make it work. I put some inspiring slides in there.
其他内容的话 我们有了任务架构 就努力实现它吧 我这里放了些鼓励大家的内容
All right, so you have a limited amount of time at this point to simplify.
现在 你们有有限的时间来简化项目
We've chosen the architecture, we know what we're going to do.
我们已经定下了任务架构 知道要做什么
There's a little bit of wiggle room right now, right?
现在还有一点回旋的余地 对吗?
We've got some play. Not a lot, but we've got some play.
我们还有一些余地 虽然不多 但还是有
There are different things that you can choose and you can change.
你可以选择 可以改变很多事情
Make sure that you're making the right decisions.
确保做出正确的决定
Focus on redundancy. Now, I'm going to go back to this document.
注重冗余备份 我们回到这份文件
Everybody take a note. This is NASA, SP 287. This is your homework.
大家可以记一下 文件名叫 NASA SP287 这就是大家的作业了
If you do not read this document, I will think bad things about you until you do.
如果你们不看这份文件 我就偷偷诅咒你们 直到你们看了为止
There you go. There's a guy out there somewhere thinking bad things about you until you read this document.
知道吧 有人会在远方诅咒你们 直到你们看了这个文件
Some things I learned from this document that I'll paraphrase, paraphrase as mine, focus on redundancy.
我从这份文件中学到的 我截取了一张图 要注重冗余
This is the ascent motor. Lots of valves do similar things. Really cool design.
图中是上升级发动机 很多阀门起相同的作用 非常酷的设计
Tests are the key.
测试是关键
This blew my mind. This chart's in here.
这个图表让我很震惊
They tested stuff, vibrational modes, triaxial acceleration tests.
他们进行了各种测试 振动模式 三轴加速度测试
They tested stuff and they shook it. You know what they found?
他们把部件放在振动台上测试 你知道他们发现了什么吗?
5% of the stuff broke because of how they did it. 1.5% on the left was due to the design of the component. 3.5% was workmanship for a total of 5% of the stuff.
5%的部件损坏了 他们是这样统计的 其中左边1.5%是部件设计问题 3.5%是因为部件加工技艺问题
This is just a representative of these stuff.
这只是其中一个例子
But they explained why and they're like, Hey, there's going to be mishaps because we're humans and all the workmanship is not going to be perfect.
但他们解释了原因 即总会有瑕疵的 因为我们是人 没有完美的工艺
You need to know it's there, need to go find it. The way you find it is test.
你知道瑕疵的存在 要把它揪出来 方法就是测试
I thought it was brilliant, man. This is an awesome document.
我觉得这真的很棒 这文件太棒了
Don't compromise on your standards.
下一条 不要在标准上妥协
Let me tell you what's going to happen. I've given enough briefings at the Pentagon.
我告诉你们 我在五角大楼做过老多简报了
Young engineers, if you haven't done that yet, you're going to do it and this is what's going to happen.
没做过简报的年轻的工程师们 你们以后肯定也会做的
You're going to get in that room and you're going to tell them, We can't do this and we can't do this because of that.
你们会进入汇报的房间 然后告诉他们 我们不能这样 不能那样 因为这样那样的原因
They're going to say, But my schedule says this.
他们会说 "但我的时间表是这样安排的"
You're like, If you do this, then you just have to be willing to say the truth.
如果你走到这步 你就必须敢于说出真相
Sometimes the manager is going to accept the risk and that's okay.
有时主管会接受风险 这没关系
You mitigate the risk as far as you can. You communicate clearly, but you make sure you don't compromise on standards.
你可以把锅甩出去 你已经表达清楚了 但你不要降低你自己的标准
The one thing that always happened is people tried to figure out how to delete tests from the test plan.
人们经常喜欢想方设法从测试计划中删除一些测试
Always happens.
总有这样的事情
Oh, man, we're six months behind. How do we gain that schedule?
"哥们 咱落后六个月了 怎么追回来啊?"
We delete that test that takes eight months.
"把那项会耗费8个月的测试取消吧"
Sometimes that's smart. They did that in Apollo.
有时这是明智的决定 阿波罗工程中也这样做过
After Apollo 8, they said in here that they were able to delete a couple of tests or a couple of shots, I forget what it was,
在阿波罗8号之后 这里写 他们可以删除一些测试或一些发射 我忘了具体内容了
but they saved a lot of time because there was one or two things they were able to mitigate the risk by cleverly designing experiments and they saved time. It's really cool.
但他们节省了很多时间 因为其中有几项测试内容 可以通过精巧的实验设计把风险转移走从而节省时间 特别酷
Crew training is paramount.
下一条 乘组训练至关重要
I think I disagree with a lot of people on this one.
我觉得这方面我和很多人观点不同
I think, and I made a video about this on Smarter Every Day, the lunar lander test vehicle, for example, if you're going to land in a 1/6th-G environment, you have to know how to do that.
我在《天天大聪明》节目中制作了一个这方面视频 我认为 以登月舱试验器为例 如果你要在1/6重力的环境中着陆 你必须亲手飞过才行
Our pilots are used to walking around in 1G.
人类飞行员已经习惯了1倍重力的环境
There's a weird thing that happens. A helicopter doesn't behave the same in 1G as it does in 1/6th-G.
在1/6重力环境下 直升机的表现会和1倍重力下不同
Neil Armstrong had a really, really interesting talk about this at the test pilot conference one time.
尼尔·阿姆斯特朗曾在一次试飞员会议上就此发表过非常非常有趣的演讲
Anyway, long story short because of time, I found the engineer that helped design this thing, the Lunar Lander test vehicle.
总之 时间关系长话短说 我找到了参与设计登月舱试验器的工程师
This is how they trained astronauts to land on the moon.
他们用这样的试验器来训练宇航员在月球上着陆
I think it's important.
我觉得这很重要
The reason this is more important than a simulator is the astronaut in the seat, their life is on the line.
这比模拟器还重要 因为坐在上面的宇航员 命是在自己手里的
That matters.
这很重要
When your blood pressure goes up and you're like, It matters. I have to get this right.
你血压会上来 你自己清楚 自己必须正确操作
That psychological training has a huge component.
这里也有很大成分的心理上的训练
I spoke to a man named Dr, not Dr. Mr. Otinger, who worked on the control system, and I asked him a very important question.
我曾跟Otinger先生聊过 他曾研发控制系统 我问了他一个非常重要的问题
I said, Well, I'll just let you hear it. Maybe I can get this right. Let's see what happens.
我说……我直接给你们看吧 我这样应该就行了
But I would like to ask you two more questions, and these are big picture questions.
我还想问您两个问题 两个有点宏大的问题
So back in the day, the engineers and scientists on this program did amazing things with limited- Analog electronics. Right. He said analog electronics.
在那个年代 项目的工程师和科学家使用有限的 模拟的电子设备
So do you think that engineers in the '50s and '60s were better than engineers today?
你是否认为 五六十年代的工程师 比现在的工程师更优秀?
No. No.
不 完全不
I think we all had our unique place in history and they'll continue to be new challenges met.
我觉得我们都有自己的历史使命 他们也会有自己的使命与挑战
There'll be innovation that continues.
他们也会有自己的创新
In part of it is because they can build on our shoulders.
一部分原因是 他们可以基于我们的成果继续前进
They can learn from what we did and adapt to the new technology and so forth.
他们可以从我们做过的事情中学习 加以新技术 如此往复
Do you think something like the LLTV needs to happen to train astronauts to go back to the moon?
那您认为 重返月球计划还需要登月舱试验器这样的东西来训练宇航员吗?
They aren't going to go if they don't get a trainer, a free-flight trainer, I can tell you that.
如果没上过能自由飞行的训练器 他们肯定不会去月球的 这我敢打包票
Really? Yeah, they won't go without it.
真的?  嗯 不飞一把他们肯定不会去月球的
They're smart enough to know.
他们不傻 知道这点
Now the United States is planning to return to the moon. Neil Armstrong.
现在美国计划重返月球  (说话的是尼尔·阿姆斯特朗)
The aircraft is on final approach to that flat tip ridge near Shackleton Crater.
画面中登月舱在沙克尔顿陨石坑旁平顶山脊准备最终下降
I hope that the person at the controls has a simulation experience that is at least as good as the LLTV provided the Apollo crews a half century later.
我希望半个世纪后的宇航员 能有当年阿波罗工程中登月舱试验器那样质量的模拟体验
Thank you.
谢谢大家
I thought that was really interesting.
我觉得这很有趣
The older generation believes in you. He said it.
老一辈的工程师相信你们
I said, Do you think the Apollo engineers were smarter than the engineers are today?
我问他 您认为阿波罗时代的工程师比现在的工程师优秀吗?
I think a lot of us today, we maybe think that about ourselves a little bit, like, Well, we got so many tools, we don't know how to do differential equations like they did by hand.
我想今天我们中的很多人也许都会对自己有那么一点看法 比如我们有那么多工具 却不知道如何像他们那样用手算微分方程
I think that. I don't know if you do. It was really encouraging to hear him say that.
我想过这个问题 不知你们如何 我觉得他的话真的很振奋人心
He said, No. The way he said it was so interesting. No, we're not better than they are.
他说不这样认为 他的解答也相当有意思 他没觉得自己比你们强
It's different and they're going to build on our shoulders.
时代变了 你们要基于他的成果继续前进
Here's the deal. There's a scoreboard, it exists.
所以回到这个计分板上来
Apollo engineers, six lunar landings, Artemis Zero.
阿波罗工程师 6次月球着陆 阿尔忒弥斯 0次
It's time to put points on the board and they've given you the playbook.
该拿点分了 然后他们把剧本递到了你手里
The playbook is called What made Apollo a success. Sp 287.
剧本名叫 "阿波罗如何成功" SP287
I would encourage you to read it if you haven't. We do not need to have an Apollo 1 type of event in order to get us in gear.
如果你还没读过 我推荐你们读一下 我们不需要再发生一次阿波罗1号那样的悲剧让我们振作起来
Don't get fixated on a technology demonstration.
下一条 不要沉迷于技术演示
Just because we can do something new and sexy and awesome and amazing and wild, doesn't mean you have to.
我们可以做一些新奇性感狂野令人敬畏令人惊奇的事情 但你不用非得这样做
Simple is good.
越简单越好
As long as it accomplishes the mission. So be mission-focused, and I think things are going to be okay.
只要能完成任务就好 多着眼于任务 我觉得这就够了
All right, so here's the thing that happens. Sometimes our thinking can get locked in on a thing, and it's like bias. We get biased on a thing.
有时候 我们的思维会被束缚在某件事情上 就像偏见一样 我们会对某件事情产生偏见
I'm going to tell you a story about how I got fixated on something.
我要给你们讲一个故事 说说我的大脑是如何被某件事情束缚的
Whatever you're doing in your job to get people back to the moon or Mars or whatever your job is,
无论你们的工作是什么 重返月球还是去火星 还是什么其他内容
don't get fixated on the way people have told you it has to be, and this is why.
不要把思想束缚在别人的说教上 听我慢慢解释
A long time ago, my buddy, Barney, he's a welder, he said, Hey, Destin, come on down to the weld shop.
很久之前 我一哥们Barney 他是个焊工 有一天他叫我去趟他店里
This was down at the missile range. Barney had built this bicycle.
店就在导弹测试场那边 Barney造了这样一款自行车
It's a really... Dad, can I see that real quick?
真的很……老爹 能帮我把车拿上来吗?
Barney had taken a normal bicycle and he had flipped it around. Check this out. Thanks.
Barney把一辆普通的自行车的车把方向反转了过来 大家看 谢谢
It's my dad. He's awesome. [Audience Applause]
这是我父亲 他老厉害了 [观众掌声]
Okay. This bike, it's really cool. It's like a transformer.
这自行车 很有意思 变形金刚一样
Basically, this thing, when you turn the handlebar to the left, it goes to the right.
简单来讲 你车把往左转 车轮会往右转
How many variables have I changed? Changed one variable.
我改变了多少个变量啊? 只改变了一个对吧
Does everybody in the room know how that thing works?
在座有知道自行车什么原理吗?
It was really, really difficult for me to learn how to ride that thing. This is the first time I was on it.
我学习骑这个车真的相当相当难 我刚骑上这辆车的时候是这样的
The faster I go the better.
我觉得骑快了会好一点
I couldn't do it.
我做不到
You can see that I'm laughing, but I'm actually really frustrated.
你看我在笑 但我内心其实非常沮丧
In this moment, I had a really deep revelation.
在这一刻 我得到了一个非常深刻的启示
My thinking was in a rut.
我的思维陷入了之前自行车的僵局
This bike revealed a very deep truth to me.
这辆自行车向我揭示了一个非常深刻的道理
I had the knowledge of how to operate the bike, but I did not have the understanding.
我自己会骑自行车 但我并没有真正理解自己为什么会骑
Okay, it's pretty interesting. Can one of you guys ride a bike?
反正很有意思 在座各位有会骑车的吧?
You can ride a bike? Can you help me for just a second? Yeah. All right. [Audience Applause]
你会吗? 想上来试试吗? 好 来吧 [观众掌声]
What's your name? Gabriel.
怎么称呼?  Gabriel
Gabriel, we don't have an SOP, we don't have PPE, we don't have anything.
Gabriel 我这没什么标准操作程序 也没护具
We're just going to roll. All right, so here's what we're going to do. Gabriel, I don't want you to hurt yourself.
你直接骑就行 你一会这样 Gabriel 千万别受伤好吧
You're wearing a suit. It's a very nice-looking suit.
这你一身西装那么漂亮
Do this. Go ahead and hop on this thing.
这样 你直接跨上来
It's going to do weird things to your brain, man, I promise.
相信我 一会你的大脑会相当迷惑
Just put your foot right there and then just try to ride, let's say, one, two, three, look, man, don't hurt yourself, okay?
一只脚放上去 尝试往前骑……这样 三步的距离吧 老兄 千万别受伤好吧
And go.
走你
You felt it, didn't you? Yeah.
感觉到了吧?
Nobody else in the room knows what it is. Try it again.
屋里没人能体会这种感觉 你再试试
Nobody else in the room knows how angry you are right now. I know.
屋里没人知道你现在有多气 但我知道
And go.
走你~
Right? Isn't that crazy? What are you feeling?
对吧! 牛吧 你感觉如何?
I don't know. It's just like I go right and I try to turn right and it doesn't work.
我也不知道 我想往右拐 往右转车把 然后就是不行
Right? Thank you very much. Give it up for Gabriel. [Audience Applause]
对吧? 感谢参与 大家给Gabriel点掌声 [观众掌声]
What's happening right now is you've got this way of thinking that you've grown up your whole life learning this way of thinking, and it's just natural.
事情是这样的 你的思维方式已经固定了 你从小到大都在学习这种思维方式 这很自然
This is what I do. This is how I do the TPS report. This is how I do the whatever, right?
我一直这样做的 我一直是这样写测试程序规范报告的 我一直是这样做这样那样事情的
It's so hard. I had to work to overcome my own brain at figuring this out.
所以我需要对抗我大脑的惯性 才能学会骑这辆车 真的很难
How long do you think it took me to learn how to ride this thing?
你们觉得我学会骑它花了多久?
Months. I did it for five minutes a day, and this is what that looks like when it finally worked.
几个月 我每天花五分钟时间 最后效果是这样的
I couldn't ride the bike, and the next day I could. It was like I could feel some pathway in my brain that was now unlocked.
……第二天我突然学会了 我能感觉到大脑中的某些通路好像打开了
It was really weird, though. It's like there's this trail in my brain.
但这种感觉非常奇怪 就像大脑中有一条模糊的轨迹一样
But if I wasn't paying close enough attention to it, my brain would easily lose that neural path and jump back onto the old road it was more familiar with.
一旦我没有集中注意力 我的大脑就会跟丢一样 马上回到传统自行车的感觉
Any small distractions at all, like a cell phone ringing in my pocket, would instantly throw my brain back to the old control algorithm and I would wreck.
哪怕有一丁点分心 比如兜里电话响了 都会把我的大脑拽回以前的感觉 然后我就蒙了
But at least I could ride it.
但至少我还是学会了
My son is the closest person to me genetically, and he's been riding a normal bike for three years.
我儿子是我血缘关系最近的人 他已经学会骑车三年了
That's over half his life. I wanted to know how long it would take him to learn how to ride a backwards bike,
相当于已经骑了半辈子车了 我想知道他学骑反向自行车要多久
so I told him if he learned how to ride a backwards bike, he could go with me to Australia and meet a real astronaut.
所以我跟他说 你要是学会这个反向自行车 就可以跟我去澳大利亚见一位真正的宇航员
Are you going to give up?  No.
你要放弃吗?  不要
Go ahead. This is how it starts. Look at this. This is such a big deal. Get up. You got it. Did you see his brain get it?
继续 这样起步 你们看 这可太厉害了 起来起来 你能做到的 你们看到他的大脑竟然做到了吗?
So he in... How many weeks have we been doing this? Two weeks?
他只花了……我们学这个花了多久? 两周?
In two weeks, he did something that took me eight months to do, which demonstrates that a child has more neuroplasticity, am I even saying that right? Than an adult.
他只花了两周就学会了我八个月才学会的东西 小孩子的"神经可塑性"真的很强 有这个词吧? 比我们大人强
It's clear from this experiment that children have a much more plastic brain than adults.
这个实验可以清楚看出 儿童的大脑比成人更具可塑性
That's why the best time to learn a language is when you're a young child.
也因此 学语言的最好时期就是小时候
So I have this weird thing in my head where as I push off, I can detect what's going on, and then my brain picks an algorithm and I can write it.
所以我大脑在我骑这辆车的时候 能察觉到发生了什么 就像覆写之前的算法一样
For time, I'm just going to fast forward to the next thing here.
然后我们快进到下一内容
It's really interesting, your brain gets in the way of your brain. That's the upshot.
真的很有趣 你的大脑惯性思维会阻碍大脑自己
So I only wrote this for like two years.
我这段内容是两年前做的
The metaphor here is, Apollo did a thing and then we came along and we started doing our stuff and we have the way we do things.
这里的比喻是 阿波罗做成一件事 然后我们出现了 我们开始做我们的事 我们有我们的方式
Do you think we can just go back?
你觉得我们能变回去吗?
Amsterdam, I decided I'm going to go to Amsterdam because I was over there doing test standards for missile stuff.
在阿姆斯特丹 我要去那搞导弹的测试标准之类的事情
Somebody said, Hey, let's go on a bike ride.
有人跟我说 走啊 咱骑车去
I was like, Yeah, bike ride to Amsterdam. That sounds amazing.
我说好啊 在阿姆斯特丹骑车 听起来很棒啊
I get on a bike and I cannot ride a bike. [Audience Laughs]
我骑上自行车 然后发现自己不会了 [观众笑声]
I straight up could not ride a bicycle.
我完全不会骑普通自行车了
Like a 35-year-old man at the time here. What do you do?
当时我一个35岁的中年男子 不会骑车 咋整?
What do you do when you can't ride a bike in a city of more bicycles than people?
阿姆斯特丹号称"自行车之都"
You start trying to justify it. You're like, Oh, no, I promise.
你开始尝试辩解: 不是这样的 我肯定会骑
People were crowding around and looking at me like, What's wrong with this American? [Audience Laughs]
旁边的人看我就好像在问: 这美国佬什么毛病? [观众笑声]
A dude can't ride a bike.
这人竟然不会骑车
I got out my laptop and I started showing these kids.
我拿出我的笔记本 给旁边的孩子们看
I was like, No, here's a video of me riding a really weird bike and that's why I can't do the normal bike.
你们看啊 这有个视频我骑着一辆很奇怪的自行车 所以我不会骑普通的这种了
This was really an interesting experience.
这段经历真的很有趣
The metaphor here is like, it's a simple bike. It's literally rocket science. It's not simple. That didn't work at all.
我想比喻的是 就像简单的骑自行车一样……好吧其实一点也不简单
But we have the test plan. We know how to do it.
我们有测试计划 我们知道怎么做
But we've got this other way that we're doing things.
但我们还有另外一种做事方式
The cool thing is you need to be able to do both.
最酷的是 你需要同时具备这两种能力
Now what I can do is I went back and I learned how to ride the other bike. Nobody record what I'm about to show you. Nobody record this.
现在我能做的就是回去学骑普通的自行车 接下来的内容请大家不要录像 谢谢
Okay, there's a cut in the video right here because I'm showing the crowd something that happened to me that's very interesting. It's a video and
这里视频我要剪辑一下 因为我要向观众展示我有趣的经历 内容是一个视频
it involves another person that was on the street and I don't have their permission to show it, so I don't want to show it publicly to the whole internet.
里面涉及到街上的其他人 我没有获得他们的允许 所以我不想在网上放这段画面
But I do talk about it when I'm giving a talky talk. It's a really fun thing I do in person,
但我在演讲中的确聊了下那段视频 很有意思
but I don't think it's something I want to put on the whole internet.
但我的确不想把它放在网上给所有人看
Anyway, it's hilarious too, and it drives some the point, which is why everybody's laughing when we go back into the footage here.
总之 很搞笑 也说明了我要表达的 也导致我们一会切回画面时会有一点笑声
That's probably enough. The point is, if you train for the unexpected, and they did that on Apollo,
行就 就放到这里吧 我要说的是 要为无法预料的事情做好训练 阿波罗就是这样做的
they had so many training plans they went through
他们准备了相当多的训练计划
that everything that came up, like over 80% of the things that happened on orbit, they already had a procedure for it. The decision was automatic.
在太空中发生的80%的事 他们都有预案 一切决策都是自动执行的
The point is, when you're preparing for this stuff, you need to train for the unexpected because you might even start surprising yourself.
而当你准备这些的时候 你需要为自己无法预料的事情做好训练 免得弄个措手不及
Everybody knows about the Apollo 12 lightning thing? Rad, right? What a great story.
av11069492
You got to be ready for that stuff.
你们要为这种突发事件做准备
This is what I wanted when I would leave, I hope you would keep this with you.
等演讲结束后 我希望大家能做到这三点
Look at the mission differently. Keep it simple.
用不同的角度看待任务 越简单越好
In a world of talkers, be a thinker and a doer.
少说多想多做
Be willing to take action. Feel free to take a picture of this if you want to.
敢于行动……这段大家可以随意拍照了
Be willing to take action in the meetings to make the hard decisions and ask the hard questions.
在会议中 敢于行动 敢于做出艰难的决定 会问刁钻的问题
That's it. I'm Destin, I hope you enjoyed that. I hope we're still friends.
我的演讲就到这里了 我是Destin 希望我们还是朋友
I hope. You enjoyed this video.
希望大家喜欢这期视频
I know this is a little different for the channel, but this was really fun for me and I thought you'd want to see it.
本期视频和以往有些不一样 但我觉得很有意思 我觉得大家会喜欢看
I had to prepare and I was intimidated by the subject matter, but it was a fun process and I thought you would enjoy checking this out.
我做了一些准备工作 有点被主题吓到 但过程很有趣 我觉得大家会喜欢看
I'm grateful to the American Astronautical Society.
我很感激美国宇航学会
There's a lot of smart people in this room and I'm just grateful to have been there.
研讨会上有很多智慧之人 我很感激能参加这次会议
My point was simplify. We've, chosen a very complicated architecture.
我的观点也很简单 我们选择了这样一个复杂的任务架构
And I think hopefully this video ages poorly and Destin ends up looking like he cried wolf because he didn't understand or he wasn't smart enough to see the blah, blah, blah.
我也希望这期视频不会过时 希望未来能打我的脸 这个叫Destin的啥也不懂叭叭给人讲课 搁那杞人忧天
I'm okay with that. Sometimes you just got to throw your hat in the ring and do the whole man in the arena thing.
我完全接受 有时候你不得不豁出去挑战一下权威
And that was what I was trying to do here. I decided to give this talk because I was seeing things
这也正是我想做的 我决定做出这样的演讲 因为我看到了这些东西
and I felt like other people saw the things and they just weren't saying them, so I decided to say them.
我感觉到其他人也看到了 但他们没有说出来 所以我决定说出来
I hope you would forgive me if I overstepped in any way. But I do think this is true.
如有僭越 望请海涵 但我觉得我说的都是事实
Also, I want to say thank you. If you're watching at this point in the video, thanks.
我还要感谢大家 如果你看到了这里 谢谢你
I mean, you are emotionally supporting Smarter Every Day by giving me your time. I don't take that for granted.
你们愿意抽出时间在精神上支持着《天天大聪明》 非常感激大家
And I also want to thank the people that support on Patreon. I do this thing every year where I thank the people that stick with me by sending out stickers.
我还要感激在Patreon上的赞助者们 我每年都会送些贴纸感谢他们
So if you'd like to be a part of the sticker team or whatever you want to call it, you can support by going to patreon.com/smartereveryday
所以你想要贴纸的话 欢迎前往patreon.com/smartereveryday支持一下
That's a really big deal when you elect to do that because it frees me from the algorithm.
你的选择这真的很重要 这能让我从推荐算法中解放出来
I can just make videos that are true to me and authentic, and that's what I want to do.
让我能全身心投入我自己想创作的内容中
So the sticker team, let me tell you how this went.
说到贴纸 我给大家介绍一下
Back in the day, people were able to get this Superstonic baseball team sticker and this James Webb Space Telescope team sticker.
之前几年 大家能拿到这个超音速棒球贴纸 还有这个詹姆斯·韦布空间望远镜贴纸
You can't get those anymore because those were people that supported on patreon the last couple of years. Check out this year's sticker.
那些你们现在已经拿不到了 因为是前几年Patreon上赞助的礼物 今年的礼物是这个
It's the smarter everyday exploration team. And I love these stickers so much.
天天大聪明探索贴纸 我真的好喜欢这个啊
It's my old helicopter helmet, and I think they're awesome.
是我的旧直升机头盔 棒极了
I spent a lot of time thinking about the size of the stickers
我花了很多时间调整贴纸的大小
because I want it to be just big enough where you might want to put it on a water bottle or a door or something like that, like a laptop,
我希望它别太小 这样大家能贴在水杯上 门上 笔记本电脑上
but not too big that it's just overwhelming whatever you're putting it on.
但还不能太大 别贴完弄得花里胡哨的
So I spend a lot of time thinking about the size of these stickers. I hope you like it.
所以我花了很久去研究多大的贴纸合适 希望大家喜欢
I've got a little bonus sticker I'm going to put in there, too. I'm not going to tell you what that one is.
还会有一些额外奖励的贴纸 就不告诉你们什么样了
But to everybody that supports on patreon at patreon.com/smartereveryday, this is my way of saying thank you for sticking with me.
所以所有在patreon.com/smartereveryday上赞助我的人 感谢你们的支持 请收下我的礼物
And of course, if you've just now started supporting, I'm going to send you the baseball as well.
当然 如果你现在开始赞助 我还会送你这款棒球
Patreon.com/smartereveryday
Patreon.com/smartereveryday
I'm so grateful that you would consider doing that because my goal is making authentic content on the Internet
我非常感谢你能考虑赞助我 因为我的目标是在互联网上制作真实的内容
while all the while pushing off the increasing pressure to make sensational content. That's not what I want to do.
而不是做各种蹭流量密码的视频
So thank you so much for considering that. That's patreon.com/smartereveryday.
所以感谢大家考虑赞助我 patreon.com/smartereveryday
That's it. I hope you enjoyed this video.
就是这样 希望大家喜欢这期视频
Thank you for emotionally supporting me. I'm grateful. I don't take it for granted. That's it.
感谢看到这里的你们 感谢在精神上支持我
I'm Destin. You're getting Smarter Every Day. Have a good one. Bye.
我是Destin 祝大家天天大聪明 拜拜